<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Portfolio on Mujeer M</title>
    <link>https://mmujeer.github.io/Mujeer_Portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in My Portfolio on Mujeer M</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 11:15:58 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mmujeer.github.io/Mujeer_Portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting</title>
      <link>https://mmujeer.github.io/Mujeer_Portfolio/post/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmujeer.github.io/Mujeer_Portfolio/post/project-5/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The dataset we are working on, is a subset provided from the original M3 competition 3003 series from International Institute of Forecasters (IIF) which is led by forecasting researcher Spyros Makridakis. This dataset is reduced to 1000 series including yearly, quarterly, and monthly micro-economic, macro-economic, industrial, financial, and demographic time series data. Our aim is to find the best fitted model for each series and produce training and test MASE results of all 3 frequencies (yearly, quarterly, monthly).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Series Analysis </title>
      <link>https://mmujeer.github.io/Mujeer_Portfolio/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmujeer.github.io/Mujeer_Portfolio/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>Diagnostic plots   Introduction Our eggs dataset from 1981 to 1996 shows the number of Coregonus hoyi of age-3 egg depositions made through the years (in millions). We will analyse this dataset to capture this trend and predict the outcome for the next five years.
Methodology  To perform this analysis we have analysed the time series plot, ACF plot, PACF plot. Applied transformation and done differencing to the data due to non-stationarity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Regression Analysis </title>
      <link>https://mmujeer.github.io/Mujeer_Portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmujeer.github.io/Mujeer_Portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>Residual Analysis   Introduction It is quite challenging to identify the quality of wine by just looking at the bottle. The objective of this report is to evaluate the relationship between variables in our wine quality dataset and identify through Regression analysis as to which variables have a linear relationship with the dependant variable (quality). This dataset consists of different variables that define the quality of the wine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Machine Learning: Prediction and Modelling </title>
      <link>https://mmujeer.github.io/Mujeer_Portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmujeer.github.io/Mujeer_Portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>Heatmap   Abstract With the dataset used in this report, we will try to predict the chances of a student getting an admission based on different exam scores and other descriptive features. We have used three classification algorithms
 K nearest neighbours, Gaussian naive bayes and Decision tree algorithms to test our training dataset which are split into 80:20 to test all three algorithms.  Introduction The aim of this project is to predict if an individual has any chances of getting admitted in given universities based on the relationship of descriptive features with our target variable(chance of admission).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data pre-processing and exploration</title>
      <link>https://mmujeer.github.io/Mujeer_Portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmujeer.github.io/Mujeer_Portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Multi-variate visualization   1.1 Objective The objective of this project is to predict whether a student’s admission is dependant on the parameters set out in our dataset. The dataset was sourced from Kaggle at https://www.kaggle.com/mohansacharya/graduate-admissions#Admission_Predict.csv [1]. This project has two phases. Phase I focuses on data pre-processing and exploration, as covered in this report. Model building is covered in Phase 2.
1.2 Dataset The dataset is obtained from kaggle and contains 9 variables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://mmujeer.github.io/Mujeer_Portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmujeer.github.io/Mujeer_Portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>You can follow or contact me through these social media platforms.
   Platform URL     LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mmujeer   GitHub: https://github.com/Mmujeer   Gmail: mmujeer@gmail.com    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>